// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "What is the purpose of exploratory data analysis (EDA) in data analysis?",
    answer: "To visualize data and identify patterns",
    options: [
      "To summarize data and draw conclusions",
      "To visualize data and identify patterns",
      "To predict future outcomes",
      "To clean and preprocess data"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "Which statistical measure is used to describe the central tendency of a dataset?",
    answer: "Mean",
    options: [
      "Mean",
      "Standard Deviation",
      "Variance",
      "Median"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "In a normally distributed dataset, what percentage of data points lie within one standard deviation from the mean?",
    answer: "68%",
    options: [
      "25%",
      "50%",
      "68%",
      "95%"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Which of the following visualization techniques is best suited for displaying the relationship between two continuous variables?",
    answer: "Scatter plot",
    options: [
      "Pie chart",
      "Scatter plot",
      "Bar chart",
      "Histogram"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "What is the purpose of a box plot (box-and-whisker plot) in data analysis?",
    answer: " To visualize the central tendency and spread of a dataset",
    options: [
      " To show the distribution of a dataset",
      " To identify outliers in a dataset",
      " To visualize the central tendency and spread of a dataset",
      " To compare multiple datasets"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Which statistical test is appropriate for determining if there is a significant difference between the means of two independent groups?",
    answer: " t-test",
    options: [
      " t-test",
      " ANOVA",
      " Chi-square test",
      " Pearson correlation"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "What does p-value represent in hypothesis testing?",
    answer: " The probability of observing the data if the null hypothesis is true",
    options: [
      " The probability of making a Type I error",
      " The probability of making a Type II error",
      " The level of significance of the test",
      " The probability of observing the data if the null hypothesis is true"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Which data preprocessing technique is used for handling missing values in a dataset?",
    answer: " All of the above",
    options: [
      " Mean imputation",
      " Mode imputation",
      " Median imputation",
      " All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "In time series analysis, what does autocorrelation measure?",
    answer: " The correlation between lagged values of a variable",
    options: [
      " TThe correlation between two different variables",
      " The correlation between consecutive observations in a time series",
      " The correlation between lagged values of a variable",
      " The correlation between independent and dependent variables"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Which data visualization tool is commonly used for creating interactive and dynamic visualizations?",
    answer: " Plotly",
    options: [
      " Matplotlib",
      " Seaborn",
      " Plotly",
      " ggplot2"
    ]
  },
  // you can uncomment the below codes and make duplicate as more as you want to add question
  // but remember you need to give the numb value serialize like 1,2,3,5,6,7,8,9.....

  //   {
  //   numb: 6,
  //   question: "Your Question is Here",
  //   answer: "Correct answer of the question is here",
  //   options: [
  //     "Option 1",
  //     "option 2",
  //     "option 3",
  //     "option 4"
  //   ]
  // },
];